hi I'm Brent contas and this video is
going to go over different types of hip
flexor stretches so the first stretch I
want to go over is just the walking knee
hug and this
one you will walk while picking up your
knee and you will I'm not going to bend
I'm not going to shift I'm going to be
in a perfectly straight line and I'm
going to pull my knee in but I'm going
to try and squeeze this glute at the
bottom at the same time p pull this up
so I'm trying to get maximum thigh
separation okay go right into the next
leg pull up squeeze this flute and you
just walk that
way um you get in a rhythm um beginners
are really uncoordinated with this
really as you as you progress you want
this to look very athletic just like
this like that and and squeezing that
bottom glute helps with the hip flexor
stretch but you're aiming for maximum
thigh Separation on that one okay the
next one I want to go over is just the
rocking soad stretch and this
one this is an Eric balance pad it helps
cushion the knee this one I am just
going to get into
position and rock back and
forth okay some people will tell you
that when you do a soaz stretch that you
want to lean laterally or you want to
rotate I don't like that too much some
people also say if you don't flex this
glute um that you're not really
stretching the so as you're stretching
the capsule or something like that and I
don't agree with that either you can
squeeze this rear glute or you don't
have to if I don't squeeze the rear
glute I can go further see how far I can
go and some people will say oh you're
going into anterior pelvic tilt and
Lumbar extension doesn't matter if you
feel it here stretching the hip flexor
that's all you need to worry about you
don't need to be so upright you can lean
just make sure you're feeling it in here
if you want to squeeze this glute it
gives a different feeling now I squeeze
the glute and you see I can't go as far
it's as far as I can go when I stretch
and if you want to lean to the side or
twist and you feel that more in here
fine but I personally don't so I don't
worry about that but I like doing
you
know like five on each side switch legs
okay and this one I don't like squeezing
the glue for other ones I I'll show you
later I do like squeezing the glue um
and now let me show you um some rectus
Fus stretches I believe that the rectus
Fus is more often the culprit and the
soas and a lot of people have really
tight W fil the problem is for the
rectus femoris it's hard for big guys
like me to to get a good stretch we're
tight and you know it's kind of
complicated so one way is
to hook your back foot up on something
like this okay and then you want to
bring your heel towards your
butt so I will just lean up like this
and just kind of hold this
position now from here I squeeze my
glute and this is going to PST to your
tilt when you PST to your tilt the
pelvis you're going to stretch you're
tilting the pelvis and that stretches
the rectus proris from the pelvis up but
the closer you can get the your heel to
your butt the better now uh I don't
personally like this stretch um I like
doing it from my side and so I will do
when I my Reus moris I would prefer to
go like
this and just kind of grab on here from
my side bring my heel to my butt squeeze
this glute squeeze it now you can
also kind of go like
this
um and
uh and grab this it's kind of hard for
me to do so but you can kind of drive
this
in and you can kind of do an active
stretch that way Some people prefer to
use a
band and they
will kind of hook this over their foot
like this and then just kind
of pull it up hook it and then that
works really well as too
uh now if I squeeze this
glute the rectus Fus stretches I really
like to uh incorporate that that glute
stretch you can use the band from a a
sideline position as
well now another tip um that I want to
give two more things about hip flexor
stretching number one I really like
doing them in a pool if you're have
access to water to a pool they're really
easy to do in a pool cuz you you know
big guys like me it's hard for me to
grab this leg you know um so if you're a
bigger guy and you have a swimming pool
do them in the pool um and then the
other thing is one that I really like
doing if you have a partner to help I
will just lay
down and and kind of do one leg at a
time and have a partner push pushing on
this leg here and just have the partner
push down to here and then squeeze that
glute you squeeze that glute and posture
tilt the pelvis and you're going to
increase the uh effectiveness of the
stretch so I'll just squeeze the glute
and have the partner pushing down you
know getting a lot of force into that
stretch and you know just maybe have
them do it for like 30 seconds
increasing the pressure letting off
increase squee the glute push down hard
um but that the the rectus florus in my
opinion is neglected and you really need
to focus on stretching the W fem out and
then the soas is is tight in a lot of
people a lot of times it's tight for a
reason and you need to figure out why
it's tight and go after that reason
which which is a whole different story
but anyway that's a video on hip flexor
stretches hope you enjoyed it